Finding aid to the Charlotte Cheever Tucker papers CA.MS.00337
Smith College Archives
Charlotte Cheever Tucker papers
1858-1979
Smith College Archives
Tucker, Charlotte (Cheever), 1858-1944
CA.MS.00337
0.833 linear feet (2 containers)
President of the Alumnae Association and member of the Board of Trustees. Contains biographical information, correspondence, speeches, and photographs.
Biographical / Historical
Charlotte Barrell Cheever was born on March 10, 1858 in Jewett City, Connecticut to parents Henry and Jane Tyler Cheever. She was a member of Smith College's Class of 1881 and later served as the President of the Alumnae Association (1883-1885) as well as on the Board of Trustees (1885-1889). After her marriage to William Jewett Tucker in 1887, she moved to Worcester, Massachusetts where she was an organizer of the Y.M.C.A. and her husband was a professor in the Andover Theological Society until 1893, when he took over the presidency of Dartmouth College. Mrs. Tucker took a great interest in music, community and public affairs, as well as in her husband's literary work. She died in Brookline, Massachusetts on April 5, 1944 after a long illness.
Scope and Contents
Collection contains biographical information, as well as information pertaining to the family's genealogy. Also included the collection are Tucker's journals, poetry, and lecture notes. There is also extensive correspondence between Tucker and her friends and family, as well as various photographs documenting her life.
Conditions Governing Access
The records are open for research according to the regulations of the Smith College Archives without any additional restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Charlotte Cheever Tucker papers were donated to the Smith College Archives from a number of sources.
- Biographical Information (Box 277)
- Biography, 1858-1917; undated (Box 277, Folder 1)
- Genealogy, 1901-1931; undated (Box 277, Folder 2)
- Journals, 1882-1903 (Box 277, Folder 3)
- Lists and account book, 1878-1928; undated (Box 277, Folder 4)
- Education, 1877-1979; undated (Box 277, Folder 5)
- Lecture notes-First Chapel, 1877 (Box 277, Folder 6)
- Lecture notes-Old Testament, 1878 (Box 277, Folder 7)
- Photographs, 1867-1910; undated (Box 277, Folder 8)
- Poetry, speech, and report, undated (Box 277, Folder 9)
- Journal, 1879 (Box 277, Folder 10)
- Journal, 1879-1880 (Box 277, Folder 11)
- Correspondence (Box 278)
- General, 1880-1927 (Box 278, Folder 1)
- Burton, Marion Le Roy, 1910 (Box 278, Folder 2)
- Caverno, Julia Harwood, 1895 (Box 278, Folder 3)
- Cheever, Charlotte to family, 1878-1885 (Box 278, Folder 4)
- Cheever, Louisa Sewall, 1917-1924 (Box 278, Folder 5)
- Frost, Mary Adeline, 1896 (Box 278, Folder 6)
- Harris, George, 1920 (Box 278, Folder 7)
- Howells, William Dean, 1923 (Box 278, Folder 8)
- Huntington, Eliza Prentiss, 1917-1931 (Box 278, Folder 9)
- Jordan, Mary Augusta, 1891 (Box 278, Folder 10)
- Kapp, Marie F., 1893 (Box 278, Folder 11)
- Rockwood, Ellen (Cheever), 1886-1927 (Box 278, Folder 12)
- Scudder, Vida Dutton, 1893 (Box 278, Folder 13)
- Seelye, Laurenus Clark, 1909 (Box 278, Folder 14)
- Tucker, Charlotte to Tucker, William Jewett, 1901-1926 (Box 278, Folder 15)
- Tucker, William Jewett, 1886-Feb. 1887 (Box 278, Folder 16)
- Tucker, William Jewett, March-April 1887 (Box 278, Folder 17)
- Tucker, William Jewett, May-June 1887 (Box 278, Folder 18)
- Tucker, William Jewett, 1901- (Box 278, Folder 19)
- Wheeler, Elizabeth (Cheever), 1917-1925 (Box 278, Folder 20)
- Woods, Robert Archey, 1925 (Box 278, Folder 21)